We've been looking at the fun of loops and you might say, well, yeah, you can see some of the practicalities
of it and why you might use the different forms in wild type loops, etc. the loops can be lots of fun,
really can be.
We're going to be looking later on when we actually get you to write your own little game.
We're going to be using a very important component of Python, which is turtle graphics, which allows
you to produce graphics, but it's all built around all the fundamentals that you are learning.
And one of those key fundamentals that you've just been learning is loops.
And so here we've got a little example on the screen where we are loading the turtle graphics into the
system.
And we're running a little thing.
Now you don't have to worry about all the details of what it means.
We just want to show you what it can do.
Looking at this code, I know some of it's going to look really confusing and not make any sense to
you at all, but don't worry, by the end it all will.
But hopefully some of this code does make some sense to you though, so as soon as you looked at it,
I'm hoping the first thing you saw was this for loop over here.
And this is one that you've hopefully written or coded a whole bunch of times already.
So for I in range 40 do something.
So in other words do something 40 times.
But now instead of just printing numbers or words or things in a list, we're actually going to print
a graphic.
And this graphic that we are going to be printing is using turtle graphics.
And it's going to come up on the screen.
But more importantly it's using a loop.
And you'll see how that works now.
Okay.
So what is this doing.
Basically if you look at it carefully, you can see all this little shape is doing is it's printing
a triangle and it's printing that triangle over and over and over again.
In fact, 40 times.
And each time.
What this code is doing here basically is it's just moving the starting position a bit, a little bit
over kind of thing.
So all it's doing is it's printing a triangle over and over and over again, but slightly moving its
position.
And by doing that, it's creating this star.
But the most important thing of this whole of the star, the reason it's here is because of this loop.
Now, when this starts to get a little bit fun, you can actually play around with it.
Let's just say we change one of these numbers to 200.
So now instead of moving that total over 144 times, I mean, instead of moving the total over 144 pixels,
we're going to be moving it over by 200.
And don't worry, I know this doesn't make much sense, but I'm just showing you how you can have fun
with it and just play around with it.
And you can see now it's still doing a loop.
It's doing a sort of triangle thing, but it's actually making a completely different pattern.
And if you look at this code, you can see it's actually pretty simple, but you can make some pretty
cool stuff.
You can change the number of times it repeats.
So it's doing it 40 times.
Obviously if you kept it going, the pattern's going to get bigger and bigger.
So lots of fun.
The whole point is that this is a demonstration of looping.
And looping is very powerful.
And when we get to using plugins like, uh, turtle graphics, you really do need to use loops to make
your screen come alive and make some fun and interesting things happen.